hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is Jeremy
Krakowski and if you haven't listened to
this podcast yet talk about ways for you
to grow your life your business if you
were a coach trainer Mentor I want to
make more money in your own business I'm
going to show you how to do that we got
over 180 episodes of this podcast over a
thousand videos on YouTube my client
growth accelerator we're helping coaches
and trainers and mentors build their
businesses to multiple six figures and I
want to help you do the same one of the
biggest things that stops people is fear
the worry
of if things are going to go the right
way if things are going to be perfect
if stuff's gonna be messed up for
instance some of you
would have the worry and fear if you
were recording a podcast episode like
this right now that you would literally
shut it off
turn your recording off
because a cat made noise
and some of you just heard my kitty make
noise and if you're watching the video
you can see Kitty on the screen here
but here's the thing
that's part of real life and and what
I've decided is this is I don't edit
things I I really don't uh when I when I
mess up when I say the wrong word when I
have sounds or noises go off or the dogs
are barking or things like that because
the truth is that's real life
this is a real life part of what goes on
and and yet there's many people who
literally like it would mortify you if a
cat was crying in your video and then
you would say oh I'm distracted by that
or I can't make my content now because
well the cat won't be quiet
letting outside circumstances
dictate what you can do in your business
you can't allow those things to stop you
and the truth is if you're a coach if
you're a trainer if you're a mentor
nobody cares about things looking
sounding perfect or anything like that
they care about are you gonna get them
results do you have what it takes to
help other people get results and now
this might trigger something and you
might be like well I don't feel like I'm
good enough to get people results
here's the thing I didn't think I was
either years ago when I started teaching
people when I started training people I
didn't think I was good enough I didn't
think I had enough information to share
with people that was that was relevant
enough for people that want to learn
anything from me or to pay money for it
let alone right
it only happened by me actually doing it
more and more I didn't sit and learn a
whole bunch I didn't listen to a whole
bunch of podcasts and while listening to
podcasts is great you're only ever going
to get better by taking action in the
face of your fear by doing the thing
that makes you sweat Bullets by doing
the thing that makes you feel fear in
the pit of your stomach
by taking action on the very thing that
terrifies you while you're afraid of it
that's what produces results and and in
in the rest of our life in in in if
you're not an entrepreneur if you're not
wanting to ever be an entrepreneur if
you're not wanting to build a business
let fear run you let fear control you
right you're still not going to
experience the fullness of life if you
do that but but it's not gonna like hurt
in the grand scheme of things but here's
the thing if you want to be a business
owner
if you want to be an entrepreneur
if you want to be the one percent of
people that make more money than anybody
else you can't let fear control you it's
not optional it's not an option
you gotta work through whatever that
thing is inside of you that's telling
you I can't because I'm afraid and
disempower it
now that might be easier said than done
here's what happens if we can identify
why we're afraid we answer that question
internally why am I afraid what do I
think is going to happen
what am I imagining in my head
here's what ends up happening as humans
when we imagine things enough it
manifests in our life because that's all
we see
all we can see is how things can go
wrong
get clear on what that is and where that
came from and often always comes from
some kind of past experience that we
have in our life that we're replaying or
something that we saw happen to somebody
else that we're replaying in our mind
and we're saying okay I don't want that
to happen to me
and I'm afraid of that happening now
here's the thing okay once you get clear
on that
don't just let it run you
if you let your fear dictate your
choices dictate the decisions that you
make dictate The Next Step that you take
you will always be controlled by your
fear it will always be the master
Commander ruler and Majesty of your life
it will be the the king of your life the
queen of your life the terror inside of
you will be terrorizing you and always
stopping you you'll always come up to it
and never go further until
you learn to take action in the face of
your fear and not let it control you not
let it have power over you
again I know that's easier said than
done
I am somebody who I've lived in constant
fear and Terror for years I was so
afraid of what everybody thought about
me if I was saying the right things if
what I was saying was coming at a cross
right to people and I was so terrified
of
what if this doesn't work out
and I was letting it run me I was
letting it dictate my life for years
you want to know what I did
two things it was helpful for me to
actually find somebody I could talk to
about it
I ended up working with a therapist to
do this I started with using a website
called
sevencups.com the number seven and then
cups
cups.com where they have counselors on
there that you can talk to and it's free
it's an actual free website and I ended
up hiring a therapist on betterhelp.com
to help me work through the triggers and
all the little fears that I had but
here's the thing you can end up getting
stuck in the therapy mindset and I want
to break you free from all of this crap
the therapy mindset is this is that I'm
constantly broken and I'm constantly
having to improve and once I finally
improve enough then I'm going to be able
to succeed but we never actually take
action because we never actually feel
like we're we're good enough
the truth is none of us are ever going
to be perfect perfectionism is a lie
thinking that you're going to improve
enough to finally take action or that
you're going to have courage enough to
finally take action as a fantasy
hear me out
take action while you're afraid
do the thing while you're shaking
do it
even when it feels impossible
and Watch What Happens
I have to do this on a regular basis on
a daily basis you might say well
Jeremiah that's easy for you you're
successful
I didn't get here
by letting fear run me
I didn't even come close
until I stopped letting fear control me
I used to let any little feeling
put the brakes on my life pump the
brakes this is too hard it's too
difficult and I would stop for months
and that might be where you're at
but there's going to come a time where
you can no longer let
pumping the brakes every time it gets
hard every time you feel afraid
be your MO
you're gonna have to learn to push the
gas pedal down when you start literally
getting that headache that you get when
you're terrified when that pit in your
stomach starts coming in when you start
shaking when you start feeling the
tightness in your neck and the tightness
in your body when you're afraid right
you get that you know that feeling and
you got to press the gas pedal down
while you're feeling that
to break past it so many people never do
this
and they let the fear run them
they let the fear control their life
they let the fear dictate
how far they can take themselves
because they got a comfort zone they
gotta they got a safety net they can
fall in
and they become addicted to that and
they say well at least I can fall back
on this
why are you allowing yourself to have a
safety net
see that's the problem that people have
is they allow themselves to actually
have a safety net to fall back on that's
a very dangerous place to be
because you'll never actually move past
that safety net until it's painful
enough for you to do so and most people
this is why most people have to hit rock
bottom in their life before they move
forward what if you could do it without
having to hit rock bottom
for many of you for most people
that's just too hard
they're just too afraid they're just too
afraid of what might go wrong what might
not work out oh I'm gonna have to dip
into my savings oh I'm afraid of looking
unprofessional oh I'm distracted what if
I'm a bad mom
for getting a babysitter what if I'm
what if what if people don't like me
what if people don't buy from me what if
they don't listen to me what if nobody
understands what I'm going through
and we make it all about us
we make it all about our worries
all we end up verbalizing is what's not
working out
instead of saying you know what I'm
feeling this way
but I'm going to take action regardless
I feel horrible right now I feel
terrified right now
I feel a pit in my stomach and I'm and
I'm shaking inside
and can't move forward but I'm still
going to do so even though it feels
impossible for me
I'm gonna make the choice to do the
scariest thing ever
what's stopping you from doing that
really answer that for yourself
and disempowering choose to tell
yourself a different story
choose to change the tape I'm gonna tell
you this in the coaching business and
The mentorship Business
it's not heart surgery
it's not that important
you're gonna have to do things in your
life that are different than how you've
always done them
absolutely
but what if by doing that
you changed everything for yourself you
set your future up to go in a different
direction What If instead of letting the
worry and the fear of the potential bad
things that might go horribly wrong for
me instead of letting those run you
you said you know what I'm just gonna
experiment I'm just gonna see what
happens I'm just gonna take action I'm
gonna step out and risk you will never
reach your goals if you don't take a
risk
you won't
there's not a like there's not some
magical sauce formula strategy of
avoiding risk there's no that doesn't it
doesn't work like that that's not
reality
your future depends on you taking risk
moving past your fear and everything
that you've ever dreamed of in your
business is on the other side of your
Fury you're going to let that fear run
you and be a roadblock for you
you have been so far
or are you gonna say you know what
I'm not going to let fear define me I'm
not gonna let my feelings Define me I'm
not gonna let what feels too hard
control me
I'm gonna decide where I'm going I'm
gonna choose to go there even though it
feels like it's impossible
I'm gonna do that thing that feels like
I shouldn't
some of you need to actually do what
you've been telling yourself for years
you shouldn't do
to actually reach your goals
we have these meanings in our life about
well I can't do that because and there's
a subconscious beliefs that we've
created about what it defines about if I
do that then I'm I'm this person
if I do that then it means this about me
and we don't ever allow ourselves to
actually move into what we were called
and what we were born to do because
we're afraid of doing what we shouldn't
so often playing it safe pleasing
everybody doing what all the people
around us tell us we should do all the
time instead of just doing what we want
what if you just did what you want for
once
foreign
what you want make you feel like you're
doing something bad
you ever thought about that
you ever thought about why you feel like
your desires are a bad thing
maybe that's what you're dealing with
and you're afraid of being bad
you're internally afraid of being a
terrible person
because for whatever reason you have
made a decision and a judgment about the
things that you need to do to actually
build your business and create the life
that you want that people that do those
things are bad people
I did that in my life
I actually had made these decisions that
the people that do what I do in business
are bad people
and the reason I wasn't doing it is
because I didn't want to be a bad person
when the truth is is that that judgment
that I had created that criticism that I
had towards another person and their
choices and what they did based off of
not having actual real information about
their life is what was stopping me
can be different for everybody
it is different for everybody
what are your fears what are your why
are you so afraid
it's time to take back the power in your
life it's time to create the life you
want instead of just saying you know
what
I'm gonna just accept the default
setting here's the thing
when you take action yes you need to
accept the outcome that happens because
you can't change what the past is you
just can't but you get to decide what
the future is and create that future and
you know what you might try to create
the future and it doesn't go how you
want it
great
that's a good thing
Embrace that
accept him taking personal
responsibility doesn't mean that I sit
around and let fear control me and Shake
in my boots
but it says I know that I'm the only one
that can create the life that I want
and so I'm not gonna let how I feel run
my life I'm gonna create it in spite of
how I feel and move forward
this is going to change everything for
you when I started doing this in my life
it started changing everything for me
I stopped worrying about
being the perfect coach
saying all the right things to make
people take action
I stopped worrying about am I am I doing
this right do I sound right
is this right
is this the right stuff
and I just started doing what I felt
like doing
I just started saying what I felt like
saying and not worrying am I going to
say it wrong am I going to do it wrong
and I I believe that you can do that as
well
in fact I know that you can do that as
well not just that I believe it I know
that you can because I believe in you
and I've gone through where you're at
I've been where you're at I was
terrified for so long
to do the very things that I do today
but it was only by me taking action
doing what terrified me
over and over and over again even when I
felt like I didn't want to do it anymore
I couldn't do it anymore that's what
changed my life and that's what's going
to change yours as well here's the other
thing I stopped verbalizing
how everything was defeating me
I stopped using my mouth to to destroy
my life
I'm going to tell you this if you keep
verbalizing how everything's going bad
for you and nothing's working out and
you're so afraid You're Gonna Keep
empowering all of that stuff in your
life now yes I still feel fear
every time I record this podcast I feel
nervous
every time I teach I feel nervous
but I no longer let those things control
me I no longer let the feelings inside
of me keep me silent and you don't have
to as well
there's no magical Seance or
fairy dust I can sprinkle on you or or
prayer that you can really say to do
this it's a it's a choice that you do
and you just you get better at it by
doing it
you get better at it by doing it an
example that I heard is you know
there's certain things in life that we
just get better at by doing
making love is one of them for instance
right you don't you're not gonna just
get better at making love with your
spouse by reading about it in a book
only by actively doing the work and it's
the same thing with moving past your
fears it's the same thing with selling
it's the same thing with coaching you're
not going to read about coaching and get
better as a coach you actually have to
coach people you actually have to do the
stuff
you actually have to do the work
and that's what's going to take you to
the next level but so many of you so
many people are so terrified of it not
working out they never allow themselves
to step into the place where they
actually learn experiment just to see
what happens just to have fun with it
and realize it's okay to make a mess
it's okay to make a mistake it's okay to
be misunderstood it's okay for things to
not work out
but that's part of the process to get
you to where you want to go
you can do it I believe in you
no more letting fear run you
we'll talk soon listen in this podcast
episode has impacted you in any way
please share it with somebody
that's all that I ask this is it's a
free resource for you there's hundreds
of episodes that can help you there's
almost a thousand videos on my YouTube
channel that can help you build your
business become the coach that you know
that you can be
so share these Resources with somebody
don't just keep them to yourself
I'd love to help you and everybody else
in your community and let's grow
together
let's create the life that only a few
have
because you are willing to do what only
a few are willing to do
your life everybody and we'll talk soon
have a good one